Preliminary Inventory to the Frank Otto Bowman Papers, 1939-1959
Hoover Institution Archives
Frank Otto Bowman Papers,
1939-1959
XX151
Bowman, Frank Otto, 1896-
1 manuscript box, 1 envelope (0.5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, memoranda, notes, military maps and charts, and photographs, relating to American military activities during World War II and the Korean War. Includes correspondence with General Samuel D. Sturgis, chief of engineers, 1951-1955; photographs and memoranda on bridge construction in Korea by the United States Army, 1952-1953; and comments by F. O. Bowman on a manuscript entitled Fifth Army Engineers in Italy, 1959.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
United States. Army. Corps of Engineers; United States. Army--Officers; Korean War, 1950-1953; Military engineering; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945--Engineering and construction; United States--Armed Forces; Sturgis, Samuel Davis, 1897-1964
Container List
- Biography of Frank Otto Bowman as of June 30, 1956 (Box 1.)
- Correspondence and charts regarding his official work as an officer in the United States Army during World War II, 1943-1945
- Official correspondence of Mr. Bowman as an officer in the United States Army during World War II, 1949-1955
- Correspondence between Major General Bowman and S. D. Sturgis, Jr., Major General, United States Army, Chief of Engineers, 1951-1955
- Material on bridges in Korea. Includes photographs and memoranda
- Reports on anti-mechanized defense and other reports, Ft. Benning, GA, 1939-1942
- Material on a demonstration of air-ground training and operations, Ft. Benning, GA, June 1942
- Comments by General Bowman on draft of "Fifth Army Engineers in Italy" by Historical Section O.C.E., August 1959
- Correspondence and memorabilia regarding Italy, 1943-1945
- Photographs. See card catalog description (Folder Photo file)